Now, in most cases,
现在 在绝大多数情况下
the behavior layer might not send
行为层也许不会发送
an exact end configuration to reach but rather an approximate one like that.
一个要到达的精确最终配置 而是像这样的一个大概配置
Therefore, we want to identify a varied goal state that leads our vehicle in
因此 我们想要确认一个变化的目标状态 这个状态在一个大概的最终配置中
the approximate end configuration that's being sent to us here in the other lane.
引导我们的车辆 它将把我们的车辆带到这里 另一条车道上
Now, that's where our sampling based approach comes in handy.
现在 这就是我们的基于抽样算法派得上用场的地方
We don't know for sure what a good end state is.
我们并不确切知道最终状态如何
Even if we receive an exact S&amp;amp;D co-ordinate from the behavior layer,
即使我们从行为层获取到精确的 S 和 D 坐标
we still have to find a good end velocity and acceleration for our car.
我们仍然不得不找出一个合适的最终速度和加速度
Most times, S&amp;amp;D aren't fixed either.
大多数情况下 S 和 D 并不是固定值
Therefore, we want to sample a large number of end configurations
因此 我们需要抽样大量的最终配置
are on the approximate desired position that we wish to drive our car to.
这些配置在我们希望到达的目标位置附近
And we generate the corresponding Jerk minimizing
然后我们为每个目标配置
trajectories for each goal configuration.
生成对应的 Jerk 最小化轨迹
Then, we discard all non-derivable trajectories,
接着 我们丢弃所有不可行驶轨迹
all trajectories that collide with the road boundaries,
这些轨迹与道路边界存在碰撞
or with other vehicles or pedestrians as predicted by the prediction layer.
或者预测层预测它们会撞上其他车辆和行人
Now, we have a nice set of derivable trajectories which are all collision free and
现在 我们得到了一些与开始以及结束配置相关的可行驶轨迹
Jerk optimal in each dimension with respect to the start and goal configurations.
这些轨迹不会产生碰撞 并且在每一维度上都是 Jerk 优化的
We need to decide which one the car should follow.
现在我们需要决定车辆走哪一条
That means we need to rank them,
这意味着我们要给它们排一下序
which we are going to do by defining a cost function.
我们可以通过定义一个成本函数来完成排序工作
What makes sense as a cost function?
成本函数会考虑哪些方面？
First, consider Jerk.
首先 它会考虑 Jerk
For each pair of end configurations,
对于每一对最终配置
a quintic polynomial is Jerk optimal.
都有一个 Jerk 优化的5次多项式
But given that all the trajectories obtained are different final configuration,
但是鉴于轨迹是由不同的最终配置生成的
maybe some are better than others.
也许其中会有一些轨迹好于其他轨迹
In addition to that,
此外
we want to consider longitudinal versus lateral Jerk.
我们还需要考虑纵向和横向 Jerk
What is worse for comfort?
对于乘客舒适感而言 哪种更不好一些？
Turns out that side to side Jerk is more uncomfortable.
事实证明 横向的 Jerk 让人更不舒服
So we want to prioritize minimizing that over minimizing longitudinal Jerk.
因此我们会优先考虑横向 Jerk 最小化的轨迹
Next, consider distance to obstacles.
下一步 我们还要考虑与障碍物的距离
Given these two configurations,
拿这两个配置来说
we would prefer being further away from
我们更喜欢离别的车辆远一点的轨迹
the other vehicle to a situation where we are right next to their rear bumper.
而不是紧紧跟在别的车辆后面的轨迹
Also, we want to consider distance to center line.
还有 我们还要考虑与道路中线的距离
We might prefer to be close to the center of the line.
我们或许更喜欢靠近道路中线
So, in choosing between these two scenarios,
因此 在这两种场景中做选择时
maybe we would prefer the one on the right.
也许我们会更偏爱右边的这个
Finally, it is time to go.
最后 车辆开始行驶
All else being equal given the final S,
所有其他值都一样地给了最终的 S
we would prefer to arrive at our destination earlier rather than later.
我们更希望早点到达目标而不是晚点
So we might prefer this situation.
因此我们可能更加偏爱这个情况
And there are plenty of other cost functions one might think of.
你可能会想到大量的其他成本函数
The tricky part is balancing all of these costs correctly.
这里的关键在于合理地平衡这些成本
Often, our goals conflict.
常见的情况是 我们的多个目标会发生冲突
So the trajectory that minimizes
所以 横向 Jerk 最小化的轨迹
lateral Jerk may not be the one that keeps us closest to the center line.
不一定是一条让我们持续靠近车道中线的轨迹
In practice, most of the hard work is in the details of balancing these cost functions.
实践中 最困难的工作大部分都在平衡这些成本函数的细节中
Now that we have defined all these cost functions
现在 我们已经定义了所有这些成本函数
and combined them into one weighted cost function,
并把他们结合进一个权重成本函数
we can look back at the scenario we just saw and use
我们可以回到我们刚才的场景
the supplied cost functions to calculate the cost for each trajectory.
并使用这些成本函数来计算每条轨迹的成本
For example, this trajectory looks nice.
例如 这条轨迹看起来还不错
However, its rather close to the boundary of the lane.
但是 它和车道边界过于接近
And even more important,
更重要的是
it is close to another moving vehicle.
它和另一辆行驶的车辆过于接近
Remember that we have to consider
我们讲过 当我们查看到障碍物的距离时
the full car dimension when looking at distance to obstacles.
我们需要考虑车辆的所有维度
And in this case, we would be dangerously close to another car.
这里 我们和另一辆车靠得太近 相当危险
Therefore, we would associate a high cost with this trajectory.
因此 我们将把这条轨迹和高成本相关联
Similarly, we don't like these two trajectories too
类似地 我们也不喜欢这两条轨迹
much because they make us drive on this side of the lane.
因为它们使我们不得不靠着车道边缘行驶
And there is not really a reason for that in this scenario.
在这个场景中 并没有理由这么做
So, they would be associated with a high cost as well.
所以 它们也将和高成本相关联
Regarding these two trajectories,
至于这两条轨迹
they're okay but the lateral Jerk associated with them would be
它们还可以 但是和它们相关联的横向 Jerk
higher than for trajectories whose end configuration has a larger S value.
高于那些拥有更大 S 值的轨迹
Therefore, they would be associated with a medium cost.
因此 他们将和一个中等成本相关联
Now, consider the last trajectory.
现在 考虑最后这条轨迹
It's nice and smooth,
看起来不错 非常平滑
it doesn't turn too fast,
没有急转弯
we end up moving further away along the road,
最终我们沿着道路继续行驶
none of our cost functions end up with a higher value.
没有一个成本函数返回一个较高值
Therefore, when we combine them,
就这样 当我们把它们综合起来
this trajectory gets a low cost and ends up being selected.
这条轨迹成本更低 最终我们会选择这一条